<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>The Snook Nook — A Whisky Blog</title>
	<subtitle>Keeping track of whiskies I&#39;ve tried</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/"/>
	<updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
	<id>https://nook.snook.ca/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Jonathan Snook</name>
		<email>jonathan@snook.ca</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Laphroaig Cairdeas Triple Wood</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-cairdeas-triple-wood/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-21T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-cairdeas-triple-wood/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The frog&lt;br&gt;
Dec 29, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nose: bacon, syrup, deep honey&lt;br&gt;
Palate: sweet and smoky, raisins&lt;br&gt;
Finish: sweet and caramel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan 20, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nose: peanut butter?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Nikka Coffey Grain</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-grain/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-21T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-grain/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When there’s a whisky that I’d pick to introduce people to Japanese whisky or just whisky in general, this is the one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, they’ll remark how it doesn’t taste like coffee. Which, it shouldn’t. Coffey (not coffee) is the type of still that the whisky is made in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s sweet caramel sugar on the nose and on the palate. It’s very smooth and easy to drink. It’s at a decent 45.6% ABV that doesn’t need any water added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikka Coffey Grain is one of my favourite whiskies and it’s a great bang for the buck. Here in Ontario, Canada, it’s $90 and I’ve seen it for as low as $55 in the States. I keep this one well-stocked and ready to go at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Black Art 6.1</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/black-art-61/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/black-art-61/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bruichladdich is such an interesting distillery with unique, flavourful expressions. The main Bruichladdich line—which includes the Black Art series—are unpeated Islay whiskies. Islay is known for its peat and the distilleries there, like Laphroaig and Lagavulin, are known for their smokey expressions. Bruichladdich has its Port Charlotte and Octomore lines for those more interested in the smokiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are here to talk about Black Art and, in particular, the 6.1. I have heard that the 4.1 is probably the best of the Black Art series but here in Ontario, if it isn’t offered by the provincial liquor store monopoly, then you’ll have to travel and bring it back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, while I can’t currently get my hands on the 4.1, I could get my hands on the 6.1. And I’m not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colour is surprisingly dark, although it is a 26 year old whisky. On the nose, I’m reminded of childhood memories at the  pool with a hint of chlorine and a strong fruit flavour like cherry ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going down, there’s vanilla and, again, a strong fruit flavour. This time, more like a strawberry-flavoured candy. Finally, I’m left with dryness and saltiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much character to this whisky. I look forward to one day trying the other Black Arts.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
