<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>The Snook Nook — A Whisky Blog</title>
	<subtitle>Keeping track of whiskies I&#39;ve tried</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/"/>
	<updated>2020-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://nook.snook.ca/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Jonathan Snook</name>
		<email>jonathan@snook.ca</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Laphroaig Cairdeas Triple Wood</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-cairdeas-triple-wood/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-cairdeas-triple-wood/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/laphroaig-cairdeas-tw.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Each year, Laphroaig releases a cask-strength edition and in 2019, they did the Triple Wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Triple Wood is matured in ex-bourbon barrels, then in quarter casks, and finally in oloroso sherry casks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, this Islay scotch comes through with a lot of rich, smokey flavour. On the nose, it’s like bacon, syrup, deep honey, and, of course, that smokiness. (I could really go for some BBQ right now.) On the palate, the taste of raisins comes through. And finally, on the finish, sweet, sweet caramel. So good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a month later, I had another dram and I swear I could smell peanut butter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its strong 59.5% ABV, I think this whisky works well without any water. Interestingly, though, Laphroaig recommends twice as much water as whisky. Adding water can definitely bring out some interesting new flavours but a 2-to-1 ratio? I’ll have to try it and report back.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Nikka Coffey Grain</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-grain/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-grain/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/nikka-coffey-grain.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;When there’s a whisky that I’d pick to introduce people to Japanese whisky or just whisky in general, this is the one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, they’ll remark how it doesn’t taste like coffee. Which, it shouldn’t. Coffey (not coffee) is the type of still that the whisky is made in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s sweet caramel sugar on the nose and on the palate. It’s very smooth and easy to drink. It’s at a decent 45.6% ABV that doesn’t need any water added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikka Coffey Grain is one of my favourite whiskies and it’s a great bang for the buck. Here in Ontario, Canada, it’s $90 and I’ve seen it for as low as $55 in the States. I keep this one well-stocked and ready to go at any time.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Black Art 6.1</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/black-art-61/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/black-art-61/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/black-art.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bruichladdich is such an interesting distillery with unique, flavourful expressions. The main Bruichladdich line—which includes the Black Art series—are unpeated Islay whiskies. Islay is known for its peat and the distilleries there, like Laphroaig and Lagavulin, are known for their smokey expressions. Bruichladdich has its Port Charlotte and Octomore lines for those more interested in the smokiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are here to talk about Black Art and, in particular, the 6.1. I have heard that the 4.1 is probably the best of the Black Art series but here in Ontario, if it isn’t offered by the provincial liquor store monopoly, then you’ll have to travel and bring it back with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, while I can’t currently get my hands on the 4.1, I could get my hands on the 6.1. And I’m not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colour is surprisingly dark, although it is a 26 year old whisky. On the nose, I’m reminded of childhood memories at the  pool with a hint of chlorine and a strong fruit flavour like cherry ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going down, there’s vanilla and, again, a strong fruit flavour. This time, more like a strawberry-flavoured candy. Finally, I’m left with dryness and saltiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much character to this whisky. I look forward to one day trying the other Black Arts.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Nikka Coffey Malt</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-malt/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-malt/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/nikka-coffey-malt.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Considering how much I love Coffey Grain, will I love the Coffey Malt just as much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coffey Grain is made from corn, giving it that mellowness. The Malt, on the other hand, is made from malted barley. It’s still considered a grain whisky, though, because it is distilled in the coffey still and not a pot still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coffey Malt comes in at 45% ABV, just like its sibling. Online review sites describe this as more fruity and spicy. My own personal notes, I found a more medicinal scent on the nose. Maybe something like a vodka flavour. On the palate, though, I could taste the maltiness and oak along with a spicy kick and then a smooth, sweet finish with a hint of vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Malt definitely has more character than the Grain but I don’t love it as much. Still decent, though. I don’t mind keeping room on the shelf for this one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Octomore 10.1</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/octomore-101/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/octomore-101/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/octomore-101.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have a love affair with Bruichladdich. Black Art, Octomore, Port Charlotte. So many delightfully tasty whiskies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Octomore 10.1 is a 5 year old scotch with a lot of peat. 107 parts per million, according to the bottle. Which seems like a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve enjoyed a few drams from this bottle and each time, I am delighted and continue to find new flavours. Initially, it was all about the smokiness—but one that differentiates itself from the kind of smoke you get from Lagavulin, Laphroaig, or Ardbeg. This evening, I swear I was reminded of wintergreen mint Life Savers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, the flavour was intense but not quite with the same complexity as the nose. The smoke is still there but a sweetness comes through, as well, along with a hint of ginger. At a strong 59.8% ABV, I find adding some water definitely helps settle the intensity and lets some other earthy flavours come through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to get my hands on the entire Octomore collection to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Aberlour A’bunadh</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/aberlour-abunadh/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/aberlour-abunadh/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/aberlour-abunadh.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One day, in the dark recesses of the internet, I came upon a &lt;a href=&quot;https://forwhiskeylovers.com/sites/default/files/user/20168/photos/Scotch%20chart.jpg&quot;&gt;flavour map&lt;/a&gt; that attempts to place various Scotch whiskies on a spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the top were those that were rich, being more sherry and fruit forward. Along the bottom were those that were lighter and more caramel forward. Along the left were peated and spicy. Finally, along the right were unpeated whiskies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once learned from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danrubin&quot;&gt;Dan Rubin&lt;/a&gt; that it’s useful in Photoshop to adjust a slider to its extremes to make it easier to see the effects it would have on the image. Then you can dial it back to something that is more modest and appropriate for the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a similar approach with whiskies. Go to the extremes to experience the intensity and then dial it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the light and soft corner were the Balvenie DoubleWood and Auchentoshan. The DoubleWood is smooth and easy to drink. It’s probably the first Scotch I tried that really hit the mark for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the peat and caramel corner is Octomore and Port Charlotte. I’ve mentioned how much I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/posts/octomore-101/&quot;&gt;a fan of Bruichladdich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the heavy sherry and peat is Ardbeg Uigeadail and Laphroaig Triplewood. Absolutely delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final corner are the sherry monsters. The Aberlour A’bunadh sits nice and close to that corner. And oh boy is it tasty. I really enjoy the sherry influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, I found it musty along with cherry, a hint of orange, and definitely that oloroso sherry influence. That sherry follows through on the palate. So rich and delicious. The fruity sherry finish leaves some spice, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batch 66 comes in at a cask strength of 59.2%. I like it neat, without water. At $100 (Canadian), I think this is a great value for a great Scotch whisky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having tried the extremes, I don’t think I’ll be dialing it back anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Bunnahabhain 1997 Palo Cortado Cask Finish</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/bunna-1997-palo-cortado/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/bunna-1997-palo-cortado/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/bunna-1997-palo-cortado.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Despite being located on Islay, known for its peated whiskies, Bunnahabhain produces mostly unpeated whiskies, including the 1997 Palo Cortado Cask Finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This expression is aged for 19 years in traditional oak and then finished for 2 more years in Palo Cortado sherry casks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming in at 54.9% ABV, I didn’t add any water. On the nose, a light buttery smell seems most prominent along with a deeper sweetness more like port or raisins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, it is rich and spicy with cherry and nutmeg. Then I’m left with a dry finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At $600 (Canadian) for a bottle (and only 1644 bottles in existence), I’d recommend getting this only if you have a particular affinity for Bunnahabhain. It’s tasty but not sure it’s hundreds-of-dollars tasty.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Macallan 25</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/macallan-25/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/macallan-25/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/macallan-25.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m not normally a fan of Macallan but thought I’d give a high-end expression of it a try. Considering how pricey this 2019 release is, maybe I could be convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The packaging is lovely. A wooden case held closed with magnets opens up to a liner describing the whisky and two wooden slats holding the bottle in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my first opening of the bottle, I gave a pour, added some water, and let it breathe for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, a definite maple syrup smell comes through but on the palate, I find the taste rather muted and underwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maple syrup isn’t a tasting note mentioned on the Macallan web site, so I’m trying it again. This time, I’m not noticing the maple syrup smell I had last time. Now, I’m getting a strong oak with citrus. Definitely closer to what Macallan says to expect; although, I’m still not getting the cinnamon they mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, I’m noticing the cinnamon but still, overall, rather underwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Thirty minutes later.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glass, nearly empty, has been sitting there. I lift it up to finish off the last gulp that remains and… there’s that maple syrup smell again. So odd. It’s still not enough to redeem this rather mediocre whisky, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s safe to say that I’m not a fan of Macallan and spending more money definitely hasn’t changed my mind.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Balvenie 14 Year Caribbean Cask</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/balvenie-14-caribbean/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/balvenie-14-caribbean/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/balvenie-14-caribbean.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Balvenie 14 Year Caribbean Cask is aged in traditional oak casks for 14 years and then finished in rum casks, although Balvenie doesn’t say for how long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 14 Year comes in at an easy 43% ABV. I haven’t added any water to my glass, but you do you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, it’s fresh and fruity. Like oranges and citrus and maybe even a hint of cherry. It follows through on the palate, filling the mouth with sweet goodness that coats the mouth and leaves that fruitiness along with some honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s $145 (Canadian) and I think it’s totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Balvenie 15 Year Single Barrel Sherry Cask</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/balvenie-15-sherry/"/>
		<updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/balvenie-15-sherry/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/balvenie-15-sherry.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Balvenie was one of the first distillers that I got into. When I get into something, I tend to go all-in on something and started buying all the whiskies that Balvenie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Balvenie 15 Year Single Barrel Sherry Cask is matured in a  European Oak Oloroso sherry butt that yields 800 bottles. Sounds amazing. It has an ABV of 47.8% which is lower than I would’ve expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My bottle has been sitting on my shelf, about three-quarters full, for a few years now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to it after all these years, I noticed an earthy, musty, plant smell. Like a dank basement. It’s sherry cask! This should be rich and delicious and it’s anything but. Did my bottle go bad? I’ve heard such a thing is rare but I don’t know how else to explain how this tastes so bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m reluctant to spring for another bottle of this to test my theory that mine has simply gone bad. Maybe I’ll find it someday on a shelf at some bar and I’ll spring for a dram in hopes that this expression is actually pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Port Charlotte MRC:01 2010</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/port-charlotte-mrc01/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/port-charlotte-mrc01/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/port-charlotte-mrc1.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Port Charlotte is a line of heavily peated whiskies from Bruichladdich, a distiller from Islay—an island known for its peat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MRC:01 is a 7 year old whisky distilled in 2010 and spends its time in first-fill American whiskey casks and second-fill French wine casks. Then combined together to spend another year in French oak from Bordeaux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, I notice orange and grass. It’s peaty but it doesn’t have the meaty or ashy smokiness of a Laphroaig or Lagavulin. There’s a saltiness like that of an ocean breeze. It feels light and cooling. The Bruichladdich site describes additional notes of vanilla, toast, chocolate, roasted coffee beans, and more, but I don’t notice them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 59.2% ABV, it’s intense on the palate. Medicinal and oaky, with a faint sweetness carrying it. On an earlier dram, I even noticed something akin to tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the finish, an ashiness that wasn’t there on the nose comes through strong. It’s like an ashtray in the back of my throat and I’m left with a dryness. There’s a bit of heat that lingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back for a second sniff, the ash is more prominent and I begin to notice the nuttiness and toast smells coming through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I add some water and notice the oakiness even more. It’s not as harsh on the palate but I’m not finding the water bringing out anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the MRC:01 an interesting whisky—as evidenced by the bottle being over half empty already. Bruichladdich doesn’t say how many of this limited release were bottled but I’ll definitely be sad to see this one disappear.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Colonel EH Taylor Small Batch</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/eh-taylor-small-batch/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/eh-taylor-small-batch/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/ehtaylor-smallbatch.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I feel like I need to preface this with the fact that I’m not a big fan of American whiskies. Or rather, I haven’t paid enough attention to the ones I have tried to understand what I like or don’t like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EH Taylor Small Batch is a 50% ABV Straight Kentucky Bourbon. That means it’s made from a minimum of 51% corn and is aged in new oak barrels. The actual ratios of corn, rye, and barley aren’t known. There’s no age statement on this particular bottle, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, it’s caramel and corn. It has a bit of sting to it as the alcohol burns its way through but it’s not too much and I’m still left with sweetness and maybe even some cinnamon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the bourbons I’ve tried, I don’t mind this one but it hasn’t convinced me that I should get into bourbons.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Weller Special Reserve</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/weller-special-reserve/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/weller-special-reserve/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/weller-sr.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Talking about bourbons doesn’t seem quite as exciting as talking about scotch. With fairly strict requirements around ingredients and casks, there isn’t much to add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weller Special Reserve has no age statement but replaces the rye in the recipe with wheat. As such, on the nose, it has more of a cereal note but still plenty of that caramel corn smell, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, there’s almost a cherry cough syrup taste that comes through. I kinda want to pair this with a cherry coke. I like this better than the EH Taylor Small Batch but I’m still unconvinced when it comes to drinking bourbon.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dalmore Cigar Malt Reserve</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/dalmore-cigarmalt/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/dalmore-cigarmalt/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/dalmore-cigarmalt.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s a blisteringly hot day today. The sky opened up and it started to pour. I went out on to my covered porch to watch the rain and enjoy a cigar. What better dram to try with it than the Dalmore Cigar Malt Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s matured in American white oak ex-bourbon casks, Matusalem oloroso sherry casks and Cabernet Sauvignon barriques. It’s a mild 44% ABV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, before I’d had a puff of my cigar, I smelled sweet plum and raisin. Maybe even a hint of green apple. That sweetness follows through on the palate and adds a bit of oakiness. It continues on down with a smooth, easy finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after the cigar is done, it’s a deliciously easy pour. Dalmore describes cinnamon, tropical fruits, banana toffee, and vanilla ice cream as expected flavours. I notice the cinnamon and some orange zest but I’ll be damned if I can taste the vanilla ice cream. Although, I could definitely go for some ice cream right now, what with all this heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I bought in too quickly to the name of the whisky but I really do enjoy having this with a cigar.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dalmore Port Wood Reserve</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/dalmore-portwood/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/dalmore-portwood/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/dalmore-portwood.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Having just had some of the Cigar Malt, I thought it’d be interesting to try the Port Wood right afterwards. Aged in American white oak ex-bourbon casks and aged Tawny Port pipes, I’m expecting some deep raisin with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, while I do sense some of the raisin, it’s not the dominant smell. Instead, I’m getting more of a bread-like scent, leaning into pretzel territory. Bizarrely, and I hate to say this, but I’m getting a hint of mac and cheese. I feel like this would pair well with a blue cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, there’s definitely some spice there, like cinnamon and nutmeg, and has some heat going down. I’ve added some water now to lessen the heat and see if anything more interesting comes out. Orange comes through on the nose. The water definitely makes it go down more easily. It has a lower, creamier note that I’m finding it difficult to describe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s not as sweet as the Cigar Malt. It’s not a bad whisky. I’d drink it if somebody offered it to me but once I run out, I won’t be buying any more of this bottle.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Collingwood</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/collingwood/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/collingwood/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/collingwood.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;My experience with whisky has been limited mostly to Japan, Scotland, and the good ol’ U.S of A. Maybe oddly, despite my residence, I haven’t explored much in the way of Canadian whiskies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collingwood is made north west of Toronto, off the coast of Georgian Bay with a blend of corn, rye, and barley. Aged in white oak barrels, blended, and then rested with   toasted maplewood staves to finish it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, Collingwood has a strong cereal note with a light fruity apple scent. Like oatmeal with fresh apple slices on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swirl it around the glass and you’ll see that this definitely has legs. Marzipan comes through on the palate. Definitely more complex than a bourbon but overly so.  The finish is warm and drying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Collingwood website says the whisky goes well neat or in a cocktail. I decided to whip up some simple syrup and make myself a whisky sour. The taste of the whisky comes through and adds a lovely flavour to the sour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At $35 (Canadian), I think this is a great mixer that is still decent (if maybe somewhat unremarkable) neat.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Little Book Chapter 2: Noe Simple Task</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/littlebook-chapter2/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/littlebook-chapter2/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/littlebook2.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Little Book is a yearly release by Freddie Noe, son of current Beam master Distiller, Fred Noe. Chapter 2, “Noe Simple Task”, came out in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Little Book is a blend of 8-year Kentucky Straight Rye, 40-year Canadian whisky—which makes me think it’s Canadian Club, and a 13-year Canadian rye. One site says the 40-year was 100% corn but Canadian Club 40 Year is a blend of 3 mash bills, of which only one is 100% corn. (Another being 100% rye and the last a blend of rye, malted rye, and malted barley.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a hefty 59.4% ABV. The first time I tried this months ago, it was strong and didn’t really appeal. Today, let’s see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, I definitely notice the bourbon at its core but there also seems to be a floral note that almost reminds me of something gin-like. On the palate, it’s definitely still intense, just like last time, but I’m noticing the spice and sweetness come through. The sweetness is fruity but like a Fruity Pebbles cereal.  I’m definitely enjoying this more now than the first time I had tried it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whisky has character but given the Canadian content, I expected this one to be smoother than it is. I’m appreciating this one more with each new sip I take. I don’t know that I’d buy this again, though. There are other whiskies that I’m more enamoured with that I’d prefer to spend my money on.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Kujira 20</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/kujira-20/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/kujira-20/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/kujira20.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Some purists might argue that a rice spirit can’t be called a whisky. I’m not one of those purists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kujira 20 is a “rice whisky” that has been aged for 20 years in American bourbon barrels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, it’s rather fascinating, with a sharp, almost chemical, smell and then a candy sweetness follows behind that. It reminds me of those strawberry hard candies that had a soft, liquid center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, it’s like buttery toffee and ginger candy. It’s a sticky sweetness. I’m picturing some spilled Kool Aid that has been sitting out for too long. It doesn’t have quite the same rounded, sake-like mouthfeel that many rice whiskies have but it’s still close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just a hint of spice lingers after it all goes down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this one was about $300 (U.S.). A bit on the pricey side—although maybe not so much for a 20 year old liquor.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Nikka Whisky From The Barrel</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-fromthebarrel/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-fromthebarrel/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/nikka-fromthebarrel.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;From the Barrel is a blend of single malt and grain whiskies from both the Miyagikyo and Yoichi distilleries. This whisky apparently won in the World Whisky Awards back in 2007 and again in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, I smell orange and caramel sweetness along with a light floral note in there. There’s definitely a similar sweet note as the Nikka Coffey Grain but with a couple more things added on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 51.4% ABV, it definitely brings some more spice and heat than the Coffey Grain. It goes down warm, leaving the mouth a bit dry along with notes of nutmeg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added some water which brought out a creaminess on the nose. It definitely mellows it out on the palate but maybe a bit too much. (I may have added too much water and I didn’t think I had!) I think I prefer this one without the water added. The complexity disappears otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Barrel is inexpensive, retailing for $70 here in Canada. (Not that stores in Ontario have any more.) Personally, I still prefer the Coffey Grain as my go-to but if you want a bit more complexity and heat, I think From the Barrel is worth a go.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Laphroaig 30 The Ian Hunter Story - Book 1</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-30-ianhunter/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/laphroaig-30-ianhunter/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/laphroaig-30.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;When I first dipped my toe into Scotch, I stuck primarily to Balvenie—a nice, easy to drink highland single malt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on a whim, I bought a bottle of Lagavulin, which introduced me to Islay Scotches. Then, I tried the Laphroaig Cairdeas Triple Wood and fell in love.&lt;br&gt;
Here in Ontario, they do allotments where you put your name in and hopefully get picked for the opportunity to buy a bottle. I put my name in, got lucky, and now have a bottle of the Laphroaig 30 in the Nook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Book 1 is a first in what will be a series of yearly releases in honour of Ian Hunter, the last of the Johnston family to own and manage the Laphroaig distillery. The packaging is definitely lovely, with a plush “book” cover that opens to reveal the bottle laid inset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whisky itself is aged in first-fill bourbon barrels. My expectation is that this might be more oak-forward with a more subdued smokiness but let’s give it a try, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, the smokiness is definitely there but it doesn’t punch you in the face. It feels light and minty and sweet and I want this smell as a cologne so I could smell it throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first hit on the tongue, those initial smells fill the mouth and then slowly evaporate to reveal more of an ashiness and a very hint of spice. The slightly salty and iodine finish barely lingers, inviting me to have some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That oakiness that I thought might be the overpowering flavour is barely there—which, in my opinion, is great. Each sniff reveals a bit more. A hint of honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suddenly have a craving for cheese. I sliced up some parmesan and Roquefort that I picked up earlier today.  The parmesan turns out not to be a great pairing. The deeper umami negates some of the flavour. The Roquefort, on the other hand, is delightful. Its softer, creamier flavour pairs better—especially when drizzled with a touch of honey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 46.7% ABV and while the Scots might suggest to add water to any scotch, I’m a-okay not adding an ounce to this fine dram. It’s perfect just the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Kaiyo Mizunara Cask</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/kaiyo-mizunara-cask/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/kaiyo-mizunara-cask/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/kaiyo-mizunara.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The description of this is interesting. Aged in mizunara casks and then taken out to sea for up to three months. A bunch of Kaiyō whiskies, like The Sheri and The Peated, have won awards but this isn’t one of them and I think that is evident upon experiencing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, there’s the smell of tap water and cedar with hint of green apple. There’s also a dull sweetness that comes through. On the palate, there’s an initial spice and then a bit of apple pastry with a lot of dry wood to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a bit of water brings out more of that sweetness but not much else. Considering the time at sea, I didn’t notice any saltiness come through in the final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the most exciting Japanese whisky. If you’re into Highland Scotches, I think this might find more appeal for you but for me, I find it bland and uninteresting. I’d rather have my go-to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/posts/nikka-coffey-grain/&quot;&gt;Nikka Coffey Grain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Matsui Mizunara Cask</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/matsui-mizunara-cask/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/matsui-mizunara-cask/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/matsui-mizunara.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Matsui Mizunara Cask won Double Gold at San Francisco World Spirits Competition in 2019 and was awarded Japanese Single Malt of the Year in Jim Murray’s Whisky Bible 2020. With that kind of high praise, I came in with high expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, it’s very light and floral. It coats the mouth and burns a bit from the alcohol, leaving a dry oak on palate. The more I smell, the more a light cherry flavour seems to make itself known. Adding a couple drops of water really intensifies the nose, bringing out more sweetness. It also reduces the burn on the palate but I feel like oak is the predominant flavour and anything else has to battle its way through to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more this sits out, the better it gets. An oily toffee sweetness is more evident. That’s one of the things about relying on awards is that it’s difficult to know how they partook of the whisky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all the awards, this doesn’t hit the mark for me. Interesting on the nose but it fails to follow through on the palate.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ardbeg An Oa</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/ardbeg-an-oa/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/ardbeg-an-oa/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/ardbeg-an-oa.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve become a fan of Ardbeg (although you wouldn’t quite know it from the lack of Ardbeg reviews on this site to date). Ardbeg, in my eyes, is up there with Lagavulin and Laphroaig for Islay distilleries well known for their peaty smoky deliciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening, I pulled out my bottle of An Oa, a whisky pulled from Pedro Ximenez casks, virgin charred oak casks, ex-bourbon casks and other unspecified casks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, ashy peat, soft oily brine, bready, and damp earth. The sweetness is subtle. There was creaminess on the palate as it coated my mouth in peat and brine and nutmeg. The flavour sticks around and the ash that wasn’t evident on the palate comes back in the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give it some time and a couple drops of water and the sweetness, more like sugar, makes an appearance. It reminded me of those old Popeye candy cigarettes. The ashiness isn’t as intense as some of the other Ardbegs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ardbeg mentions dark chocolate, black pepper, butterscotch, and aniseed notes, as well, but none of those really came through for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I like the balance the An Oa has. It’s definitely a good one to get introduced to Ardbeg.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ardbeg Uigeadail</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/ardbeg-uigeadail/"/>
		<updated>2020-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/ardbeg-uigeadail/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/ardbeg-uigeadail.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In 2009, Jim Murray’s Whisky Bible named Ardbeg Uigeadail (pronounced Oog-a-dal) World Whisky of the Year. Over 10 years later and I think this one is still near the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong phenolic right off the bat with a meatier ash coming in behind it followed by those hints of candy. Definitely scents of raisin, to be expected from the ex-sherry casks. Finally, noticing more bready notes towards the end. Like Christmas Cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oogie has a deeper, sweeter flavour than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/posts/ardbeg-an-oa/&quot;&gt;An Oa&lt;/a&gt; with a more intense cigar ash to it. That ash follows on through to the palate and the finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, that ash is strong and comes with a sherry sweetness. I don’t want to downplay the Uigeadail but I don’t find as much variety in the notes to this whisky as say, a Bruichladdich. To be clear, this isn’t a bad thing. It’s just different and sometimes I’m in the mood for one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the Uigeadail is very much about the smoke and sweet. I love the smell of the smoke from the beginning right through to the end. I’ll leave the glass on the kitchen counter overnight and it’s like a beautiful candle has been left on when I walk into the room in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite Islay scotches and have made sure to have a couple bottles in the collection for backup.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Orphan Barrel Rhetoric 24</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/rhetoric-24/"/>
		<updated>2020-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/rhetoric-24/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/rhetoric-24.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Orphan Barrel is a distiller from Tullahoma, Tennessee, focused on making rare whiskies. The Rhetoric series is a gradual aging from 20 to 25 years. I picked up the 24 in hopes of finding a bourbon that hits the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the nose, there’s a strong smell of cherry syrup with a bit of cinnamon and orange peel. There’s also a rounded, almost chemical smell that I just can’t place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the palate, it’s smooth and easy. Oh, this is the first time I’ve actually noticed that dark chocolate flavour come through. It, along with that cherry, reminds me of Lowney Cherry Blossoms I’d have when I was younger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s a hint of a lingering spice but overall, super smooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a bourbon I enjoy. (And look at that…the 25 is available at the liquor store near me.)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Old Ezra 7</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/old-ezra-7/"/>
		<updated>2020-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/old-ezra-7/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/old-ezra-7.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Lux Rows Distillers has an interesting history in that they have traditionally had others distill for them until they built their own facility a couple years ago. Old Ezra was distilled by Heaven Hill, who have a whole slew of brands under their belt like Elijah Craig, Old Fitzgerald, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old Ezra 7 is a barrel strength whisky coming in at 58.5% and it’s very noticeable. It has a kick to it as it warms the mouth and throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t find it stood out from other bourbons. It has that familiar cinnamon and orange peel bourbon smell with very little of it separating it from the rest, except maybe a hint of hazelnut.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Port Charlotte Islay Barley 2011</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/port-charlotte-barley/"/>
		<updated>2020-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/port-charlotte-barley/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/port-charlotte-barley.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Islay Barley 2011 is part of Bruichladdich’s heavily peated Port Charlotte line that uses 100% Islay barley. It’s 75% first fill American whiskey casks and 25% second fill syrah and figero wine casks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I pour, I notice lots of cling on the side of the glass. The smell of the peat is strong at first. I had let it sit for about 15 minutes while I took photos and that strong peaty smell got a lot more mild. (Or I became a lot more accustomed to it.) There’s a very light hint of lemon. Despite leaving it out, it’s really intense on the palate. The medicinal flavour is present but slight. The ashiness is present but slight. (I expected plenty more ashiness.) There’s a bit of white pepper and brine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the barley and nuttiness on the finish. I let it sit on the palate a bit longer and I’m reminded of Arrowroot cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the initial peaty punch, it’s a bit…disappointing. It’s still decent but didn’t quite reach the same level as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/posts/port-charlotte-mrc01/&quot;&gt;MRC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruichladdich’s notes talk of lemon, peach, and green grapes on the nose. “Some time to open allows notes of lemon drizzle cake,” they say. Which definitely matches what I was noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the finish, they mention tar and brine, coconut and tobacco. I didn’t notice the tar or the coconut but definitely picked up the brine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A dram for summer nights.” Its lightness on the palate has me in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Lagavulin 8</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/lagavulin-8/"/>
		<updated>2020-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/lagavulin-8/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/lagavulin-8.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Perhaps unfairly, my introduction to the world of Islay whiskies was the Lagavulin 25—an expensive but worthwhile lesson in how divine an Islay whisky can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to check out the rest of the Lagavulin lineup. Thankfully, it’s not that large. There’s the 25, the much-enjoyed 16, and the more recently introduced 8. Outside of that, they have their yearly releases of 12 and 16 Distiller’s Edition. Thrown in a couple co-branded bottles like the Nick Offerman 11 and the Game of Thrones 9 and you’re all set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I open the 8, I’m surprised by its light white wine colour.  On the nose, it’s peaty but not smoky like bbq or ash. It feels light, salty, and slightly fruity like honeysuckle. On the palate, a hint of sweet and floral quickly followed by the alcohol evaporation filling the mouth leaving a smoky, dry finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That smokiness comes through on the finish. Not as ashy as you might find in an Ardbeg. It’s meatier than that (but not overly so). But it’s still there where it wasn’t as apparent before. Finally, just a hint of dark chocolate at the back of the throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be a young spirit but it’s got plenty going for it to make it worth having.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Lagavulin 12 (2019)</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/lagavulin-12-2019/"/>
		<updated>2020-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/lagavulin-12-2019/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/lagavulin-12.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The 12 year old Lagavulin is a yearly release, similar to the 16 Distiller’s Edition. Unlike the Distiller’s Edition, the 12 comes in at a much higher ABV of 56.5%—the highest of the entire lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I pour, I notice the similarity in colour to the 8. Maybe a hint darker but still rather light. The 12 is from refill American oak barrels, so you’ll not see the deep colour you might get from a sherry or wine cask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very mild on the nose—lighter than the 8 and the 16. On the palate, for the higher ABV, it doesn’t hit as hard as I would’ve thought. In fact, it’s very similar to the 8, being easy at first until the alcohol evaporates and fills the mouth, leaving it dryer but not as dry as the 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I go back to smell it, I notice a bit of green grass on the nose. A little minty. I’m not getting the strong smoke, though, that I’d expect out of a Lagavulin (and that most reviews of the 12 indicate is there). Some slight coastal notes. I may have overwhelmed my schnoz on an earlier tasting of the 8. As I continue to partake, a bit of soapiness even appears. I’d chalk this up to more floral notes that are coming through. Definitely more heat on the second sip but still sweet and leaving my mouth drier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added some water and &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt; is the smoke! It really showed up now. I really think this one needs the water. It brings out everything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average ratings—which include ratings for all 19 years the 12 year old has been available—are around 90/100. Personally, I’d rate this particular edition around an 80/100. It’s good but not mind-blowing. I enjoyed it and, yet, I don’t feel inclined to pick up this up every year. In looking through all the reviews on Reddit, it looks like previous years hit the mark more than the 2019 release. How much you enjoy the 12 might come down to what year you manage to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Glenfarclas 40</title>
		<link href="https://nook.snook.ca/posts/glenfarclas-40/"/>
		<updated>2020-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://nook.snook.ca/posts/glenfarclas-40/</id>
		<content type="html">
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/img/glenfarclas-40.jpg&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve heard many good things about Glenfarclas and after watching the movie, The Gentlemen, where the 40 is featured prominently, I figured if there was an opportunity to try it, I’d take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, getting a particular bottle of whisky in Ontario can be difficult and doubly so during a pandemic. One company is authorized to do auctions in the province and the company puts an auction on every quarter. I took the opportunity to fill out my collection further and the Glenfarclas was just one of those opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cracked it open and the first whiff was buttery sweet. I let it sit in the glencairn and kept going back to smell it some more. After a minute or so, a little but of lemony orange citrus came through. A few minutes more and it deepens into honey, peach, pear, and raisin. The more I wait, the more raisin comes through. I am delighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First sip had a surprising amount of heat that thankfully goes away on subsequent sips. Other reviews I’ve read describe it as oily but I am unsure if that referred to the taste or the texture. Texture-wise, for me, it felt like water, which I rarely get from whisky. It didn’t coat my mouth but rather clung to itself. Taste-wise, though, the initial sweet quickly disappears and is replaced with woodiness, a bit of peppery spice, and a hint of black tea. My mouth is left dry and oaky, like I just had some white wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I keep going back to this, I’m enamoured by the smell. Every time I bring it up to my nose, I’m delighted. If anything, I’m slightly disappointed by the taste that doesn’t quite live up to that smell. It’s still delightful but not &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; delightful. The sherry influence lingers in my mouth for minutes afterwards, closing the circle on that lovely nosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider this an excellent whisky but one that still has a bit room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thenook@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

    </content>
	</entry>
</feed>
